<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Paleocomputing: restoring the artefacts of Silicon Valley, a tale - William Jolitz</title><link>https://symmetric.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 15:01:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>A heartbeat beckons...</title><link>https://symmetric.github.io/A-heartbeat-beckons.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A stack of six 375 systems. Plug one in, turn it on. Four show some kind of life, with a fifth iffy. And so it begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 1980's, Symmetric Computer Systems started from an ungainly wirewrap prototype that ran a 32 bit virtual memory,
demand paged timesharing system based on 4th Berkeley Software Distribution. I've been asked for them as historical examples
bound for the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before they go, they are being fixed up, made functional with all the ancient baggage of hardware/software best arranged. And a
copy here of the content as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the hundreds of systems spread over the global, a handful still survive. I can still tell you stories of each of them, from the first to the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of this, they can be repaired, made operational, and the bits extracted. Lynne suggestted documenting this so that others might learn/see 
how to go about this, for it's not for the weak of heart. Just in the few moments of starting this, we appeared to lose and then regain the battle
many times. Perhaps understanding the strange durability of this 30 year old technology might help others similiarly uncovering the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First lesson - isolate the power supply with a accurate load of each voltage output, then adjust to slightly above spec. Do so including
related hardware like the console terminal(s) - you'll find they are considerbly lower than before, and the ripple will be significant. Anything
that depends on old capacitors is on delicate ground. Also, RS-232 serial communications level shifters may not be reliable - didn't know that two
systems were working until a Macbook dongle with correct serial signals/parameters received a ROM monitor prompt where the terminal didn't (greater
range of signal tolerance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey begins with that message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symmetric 32000 Monitor (1.9) 375(bill) 1/6/86 18:11:15
E SVC
*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big thank you to my friends at the Computer History Museum, Clem Colea's encouragement, some of the 375's user base,
my coauthor Lynne (wrote the 375 manual, assembled/tested hundreds of 375's), son Benjamin, and daughter Rebecca who have encouraged me to accomplish this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">William Jolitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 15:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:symmetric.github.io,2019-11-17:/A-heartbeat-beckons.html</guid><category>about</category><category>beginning</category><category>symmetric</category><category>375</category><category>vintage</category><category>computer</category></item></channel></rss>